Thank you, Mr. Chairman, and thank you,
Speaker 1: Mr. Donahoe. It is good to see you again. Good to see
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): you. I have a few questions. When was the last year the Postal Service had a profit?
I
Speaker 3: think we had a profit in 2006, maybe 2007. I can't be 100 percent sure of one of those two years.
Okay, thanks.
Speaker 4: How much money did the Postal
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): Service lose in the first quarter of 2012? With our requirement to pre-fund about $3 billion and $300 million. And
Speaker 6: how much do you expect to lose for the entire fiscal year? Depending on
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): how we finish the year, probably in the vicinity of about $14 billion. We are a little ahead of our revenue.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): revenues right now and people have done a great job holding costs. The pre-funding for this year counts for both this year and last, so that is $11 billion of those. Last
Speaker 8: year,
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): Congress acted at the last second to give you some temporary relief from the pre-funding.
What
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): does the lack of certainty of whether or not you will have to make your payment each year do for your plan for profitability and your overall business model?
We
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): have to get that resolved. That is what we are proposing right now in terms of the health care proposals and the overall plan. But I will tell you, it is much larger than us. This is an industry issue.
People, to give you an example, in terms of the health
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): If you are worried
Speaker 9: about the Postal Service being able to deliver your bills and statements and you are worried
Speaker 10 (lower-pitched voice): about your cash flow as a large company, you are going to start thinking about alternatives. The faster we get this resolved, the faster people don't have to worry about alternatives to the mail.
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): That echoes nicely with my next question. In November 2011, you addressed the National Press
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): Club, and according to the transcript,
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): "You know that phrase speed kills. Well, the lack of speed will kill the Postal Service. There is a stark choice,
a more
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): flexible business model that allows us to control costs quickly or very large losses that will ultimately burden the taxpayer." If immediate action is needed to return the Postal Service to solvency, why did
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): it decide to self-impose a five-month moratorium on closures and consolidations of its facilities?
We
Speaker 9: were approached by members of the Senate and they asked
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): us, in order to keep some stability with the employees and the customers, if we would agree to wait to give them an opportunity to get legislation out and over to the House and get the legislation through the House and up to the President for signature. I didn't think that was an unreasonable ask. As we worked through these processes to consolidate facilities.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): It is not going to happen all at once. The way we consolidate will be done in a very thoughtful and careful method so we don't disrupt service. We are looking for the bottom line cost reductions, and we will get those, but these consolidations will happen over the course of the next year.
So
Speaker 12: you were supportive of the Senate's request? They
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): asked me for that consideration.
I
Speaker 13: had no issue with that. Chairman Ross and Chairman Iser wrote a comprehensive
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): postal reform bill last
year
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): that was passed by the subcommittee and the full oversight committee.
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): It is full of cost saving measures that will revitalize the Postal Service. What parts of H.R. 2309 does the Postal Service support?
We
Speaker 14: support the FERS refund.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): We support the ability to move and consolidate the network. We support the ability to move to consolidate from six day to five day
delivery.
In your
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): written testimony,
Speaker 15: you mentioned
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): establishing a Postal Service-sponsored health care program
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): represents the largest part of the Plan for Profitability Savings, accounting for over $7 billion of annual
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): savings.
Does
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): the Postal Service have the resources to maintain its own health care plan? What
we
Speaker 16: would do for a health care plan is what any other company does. You go out into the free
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): market, you bid that, you find the best health care provider to act as pretty much an overall health administration firm, say a Blue Cross or a UnitedHealthcare. We would also expect to use it.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): HMOs or other health care to fill the gaps because there are gaps out there and that is the way that we would manage it. We would go out through a regular competitive request for proposal and once we were able to secure the health care, the provider would manage a plan for us.
Speaker 17: And how long do you think it would take to implement such
a plan?
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): We have had some discussions with health care companies to understand that, to actually test out our ideas and see if they are sound. We would have to go through a request for information on RFI to get more and then go out with an actual bid. We think that we would be able to have a health care plan
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): ready by 2014. Thank you,
Speaker 18: Mr. Donahoe.